Eyüp Sercan UYGUR

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

sercanuygur@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Experienced working with React and Rails. Developed one MVP e-commerce app from bottom to top which uses Rails Backend and React Frontend. Built several client-side apps. I have excellent knowledge of Vanilla JavaScrip, Ruby and have a solid foundation in mathematics. Currently working as a part-time Technical-Support-Engineer.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD,

Chrome Dev Tools, Matlab

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

Microverse Remote

Technical Support Engineer 10, 2020 – Present

- Controlling the students' pull requests for given instructions.
- Give them the necessary feedback to achieve mastery on the topic.

Freelance Web Developer Remote

Developer 03, 2020– Present

- Worked on several business sites from the beginning.
- Open-source contributions are being added to the GitHub society.

Helios Enerji Yatırım Tic. A.ŞIstanbul, Turkey

Project Engineer 04, 2017- 12,2017

- 60 MW solar plant has been constructed.
- Worked on a 20 million dollars + project, general coordination, and project disquisitions
- Project end.

Tubitak Project (213M511), Tubitak Project (111R017), Tubitak Project (213M511)Istanbul, Turkey **R&D Engineer**01, 2014-03,2017

I worked as a researcher for three projects with Tübitak. In this role, I needed to be highly organized and efficient, and manage teams. Part of my role was keeping clear and concise records, writing reports, testing systems, and monitoring and evaluating each project's success. Part of my success in this role was my effective communication skills and flexibility.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Month, Year - Month, Year

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

Istanbul Technical University

Master of Science, Energy Science(Discontinued) 10, 2017 – 12, 2019

- Learned deeply the differential equations, finite element analysis.
- Learned the applications of renewable energy, heat transfer.
- Worked on photovoltaics and capacity improvements on them.
- Specialization in CZTS based photo-cells.

Bachelor of Science, Metallurgical and Materials Engineering 10, 2008 - 01, 2016

- Got knowledge of materials mechanics.
- Worked on the energy materials, production, and characterization.
- Specialization in lithium-ion batteries.

CERTIFICATIONS

- **Library and Frameworks**: Bootstrap 4, Node.js, Express and MongoDB, CSS with Sass, jQuery, React, Rails
- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Ruby

REFERENCES

Ömer Faruk Tuna, Helios firm partner, omer.tuna@hunholding.com

Coşkun Fırat, ITU Energy Science and Technology professor - firat.cf@gmail.com

Civan Mert Akın, TEI Special Process Quality Engineer - civanmertakin@gmail.com